{
    "id": "7e010f957dd9431e941ddeb9309dcacd",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I may leave tomorrow. /James said that he ......................... leave the next day.",
            "description": "May in direct speech becomes might in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "might",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am busy now. / Rahul said that he ............................ busy then.",
            "description": "Simple present in direct speech becomes simple past in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are sacked. / The manager said that I ............................ sacked.",
            "description": "Simple present in direct speech becomes simple past in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "have been",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What are you doing there? / He asked me what ............................... doing there.",
            "description": "In reported questions, the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was",
                "am I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are a great mentor. / I told him that he ........................ a great mentor.",
            "description": "Simple present in direct speech becomes simple past in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We might go camping next week. / She told me that ............................. might go camping the following week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "we",
                "she",
                "they"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am leaving. / She told me that she .................................",
            "description": "Present continuous in the direct speech becomes past continuous in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "was leaving",
                "has been leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Who are you? / The watchman asked me who ....................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "were I",
                "I was"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The exhibition ended yesterday. / The tourist guide told me that the exhibition ............................. the previous day.",
            "description": "Simple past in direct speech becomes past perfect in indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "ended",
                "have ended",
                "had ended"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Let's go for a walk. / He said that they ................................... for a walk.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have to go",
                "may go",
                "should go"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Close the door. / He ordered me ........................... the door.",
            "description": "Imperatives are usually reported with a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "that I close",
                "to close",
                "closing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Be careful. / She advised me ................................ careful.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that I be",
                "to be",
                "to being"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}